(futuristic instrumental music)
(electrical zapping)
- [Instrumental] Now we've
added all of our buttons
and our title text to our game.
But these buttons don't
actually do anything,
so we'll need to create a script to do so.
One thing that we're gonna
do is just some clean up,
so, in fact, because we
copied that restart button
and duplicated it, if
you go to the on click,
if you select one of the
buttons in the Inspector
and scroll down, you can actually see
that it's still tied to the restart game
and we don't want these buttons to just
be restarting the game all the time.
So actually, in on click,
you can see the little minus button,
and if you just click that,
it'll remove that game manager.
So, go through each of
the different buttons,
remove those, so now,
we can't just magically
restart our game.
Definitely don't want that to happen.
Now what we're gonna do
is we're actually going
to make a new script now.
So in our Scripts folder,
we right-click, Create,
a C# Script.
And this script will be
called difficulty button,
to control the difficulty
when we use our buttons.
So we have that.
Now what we're gonna do is
we're going to actually select
all of our different buttons,
our easy, our medium, and our hard button,
and we're going to
scroll all the way down.
Now I'm going to add a component,
and we're going to actually search
for that difficulty button script.
There you go.
Now the difficulty button has been added,
and we can actually check each one.
One, two, three scripts.
Perfect.
Now, in our difficulty button script,
in order to interact
with those buttons again,
we need to make sure
that we use that library
that we had before, very handy.
So, UnityEngine.UI,
because the UI library helps
us interact with buttons.
So now, we need to get
references to our buttons,
so we'll make it private,
and we'll just call it button,
and we'll name it button,
cause we're getting this button,
so, in our start method,
we're just going to make sure
that we get the actual button component
on our button, so we
use our button variable,
and we get the component.
And we're looking for the
component called a button.
And then, make sure you add parentheses.
So now, we've attached
the scripts on to each
of our different buttons,
and we're making sure that
we get that button component
from our button, so we
can get a reference to it
in our difficulty script.
So, what you're gonna do
is, in each of your buttons,
make sure that you go
to the on click section
underneath the button components,
remove the reference to the game manager
on each of your different buttons.
You're then going to create
a difficulty button script,
and then make sure that you attach it
to each of your easy,
medium, and hard buttons.
And then, in your
difficulty button script,
you're going to make sure that
you use the UnityEngine.UI
so we can use buttons.
We're going to make a private variable
for our button component on our button,
and then in our start method,
we're going to make sure
that we get the variable
of our button and set it
to the button component
currently on our button.
Now it's your turn.
(futuristic instrumental music)