(electronic music)
- [Tutor] We've come a long way
in our prototype adventure here.
So, we've learned a whole lot
and added even more to this game.
We have this title screen
that has text on it.
We have a score that keeps
track, we have these buttons
that can actually tell
how difficult the game is.
With each of these buttons
we can make all of these different objects
spawn faster or slower.
And if we miss one of these
boxes, our game is over.
We can't click the boxes.
If we restart our game,
it reloads the scene.
So now we have a really full
functioning game on our hands.
We learned a whole lot of
programming along the way,
like learning how to
use listeners on buttons
to be able to use different methods.
We even used methods from
other scripts that we wrote
with parameters that
we can pass into them.
We learned how to use
this division operator,
similar to how we had multiplication
and addition and subtraction,
and we figured out this handy little trick
to be able to disable all
of our title screen elements
by nesting them underneath
our title screen game object,
and turning it on and off.
With the end of the prototype
we've come such a long way,
we've added all of this
amazing UI to our game,
like buttons and text.
We learned about mouse and click events,
like clicking on this button.
We learned about game states,
like restarting our game,
setting the difficulty for our players,
enabling them to actually
play and experience
the thing that we've created.
And with that, our game is
over and our prototype is over.
We'll see you soon.
(electronic music)