(soft music)
- [Male Instructor] On
each of our buttons,
we've now applied scripts to them,
and now we actually want to use a method,
so that way, our buttons know, what to do.
Now, in our difficulty buttons script,
we're going to create a new method,
this one will just make private,
so we'll just say void set difficulty.
'Cause I don't believe
we'll need this later,
we'll just need it inside of this class.
And then, for set difficulty,
we're just going to test
and see if it works for now
using a debug.log method,
so that way we can print
out to our console in Unity,
and we're actually going to
get the button.gameObject.name,
so this will give us
the name of our button.
Then, we'll use a literal
string, to say, was clicked,
so then when we press one
of the buttons, for example,
it should say easy button was clicked.
And then, one thing we do
need to do, is we actually
need to use this method to
see when a button was clicked.
So, we can actually say button.
Now, similar to what we had
with the restart button,
where it had an onclick
method, to listen for when
the button was clicked by the mouse,
we can actually use that
in code, so we can actually
use onclick, so when
the button is clicked,
we need our game to
listen, to pay attention,
to when it's actually been
clicked, so in this case,
in programming we call
this adding a listener,
so that way it pays attention
for when a certain event has happened.
In this case, a click event.
And then, we can just use a
method to pass into our listener
so we can actually just
use our SetDifficulty.
So, when our button is
clicked, then it will go
into the SetDifficulty method,
and then we should see
which button was clicked.
So, if we test this out in
Unity, I happen to already
have my console window, as a tab here,
so we'll keep this open.
If I press play.
And I click the easy button,
easy button was clicked,
hard button, hard button was clicked,
medium button, medium button was clicked.
Awesome, so, we know that our listeners
were set up properly.
So, what you're gonna do,
is you're going to create
your own, private method, it'll
be void called SetDifficulty
just a test, and see that
it works, you're going
to use a Debug.Log method,
so that way we can print out
the name of the button that was clicked,
and then in our start method,
you're going to make sure
you add a listener to your
button, for the onClick event,
and when the button is clicked,
it'll go into the SetDifficulty method,
and it should trigger this
message in your console.
Now it's your turn!
(soft music)