(techno tones)
- [Instructor] So, our game
is just about there.
We have our title screen.
We can click on one of the buttons.
We have all of these objects that spawn.
We lose the game.
We can restart,
reload our scene.
We've got our title screen again.
The last thing we need to do
is actually make these
difficulty buttons work,
and then our players can
have a little bit of fun.
In our code,
in our difficulty button script,
we're going to create a public variable,
so we can assign them immunity.
This will be an integer,
if we're looking for just whole numbers,
and we'll call it difficulty.
Now, in Unity,
if we go to each of our buttons,
and we scroll down,
you can see that the
difficulty variable can be set.
So, for Easy,
we'll make the difficulty one.
For Medium, we'll set
the difficulty to two,
and for Hard, we'll set
the difficulty to three.
Yeah, because each of
these different buttons
all control there own variables.
It will be really easy to use them.
In our GameManager script,
we should go down to StartGame,
since that's what the
difficulty buttons are using,
and I'll actually pass in
an int difficulty parameter,
so that it will use this integer,
and then,
lucky for us,
because we actually
made a spawnRate before,
we can actually now use that variable
that we thought of before
to control our difficulty.
So, if we set our spawnRate,
and in this case,
we want our spawns to happen faster,
so we'll divide spawnRate
by the difficulty
that's passed in from our buttons.
So, when we pass in our
difficulty from our buttons,
for example, our Easy button,
our spawnRate here,
which is currently up to one second,
will be divided our Easy difficulty,
which is one.
So, one divided by one,
means our spawnRate will stay at one.
If we pass in our Medium button,
then our difficulty becomes two.
So, it will be one divided by two,
which is 1/2, or 0.5 seconds,
and if we use our Hard difficulty,
it will be divided by three.
So, one divided by three,
is 1/3, or 0.33 seconds.
If you remember, there's one little bit
of cleaner code that we can write.
So, this is pretty redundant, right here.
In fact, we can use the
same style of operator
that we used for adding
and multiplying values
that we were trying to multiply
themselves against other things.
So, if we do spawnRate
forward slash equals difficulty,
this means spawnRate is set to,
spawnRate divided by our difficulty.
Make sure we save that,
and now, in our difficulty button script,
StartGame is a little annoyed with us,
so we'll pass in our difficulty variable.
So, whenever one of the
different buttons is pressed,
it will send in that
difficulty to StartGame,
send that information to our GameManager,
which will then use
that updated spawnRate,
to spawn enemies faster or slower.
So, now we're really communicating
between the different
scripts that we've written.
Very similar to how we
were learning how to use
methods and parameters before.
If I save this,
and now, in Unity,
when I go to my game,
in this case I will select
the Maximize On Play button
on my game window,
so when I press play,
our game goes full screen.
If I press one of the buttons,
so, Easy,
we should see a fairly slow spawnRate.
If I restart,
and I press Medium,
it should be a little bit faster.
That's very fast,
lot of skulls,
and if I restart one last time,
Hard mode, should spawn
a lot of boxes very fast.
I can't even click on all of them.
So, what you're gonna do,
in your difficulty buttons script,
add a public variable
that's an integer for your difficulty.
In Unity, select each of your buttons,
and now that you have
that difficulty variable,
you can set each one to be
one, two, three,
however difficult you want it to be.
In our GameManager script,
if you go to your StartGame,
pass a parameter into
it using int difficulty,
add a parameter with
our spawnRate variable.
We're going to divide
that by the difficulty.
So, that way our objects spawn faster,
and then finally in difficulty button,
under set difficulty,
make sure you pass the difficulty variable
into your StartGame method.
Then test your game one final time
using the Maximize On Play button
in your game window.
So, when you press play
your game goes full screen.
Now, it's your turn.
(techno tones)