(game music)
- Our game is so close to being done.
If we play our game,
You see now, none of
these boxes spawn anymore.
But then when we click
one of the difficulties,
then our boxes start spawning.
The problem is, they don't
go away when the game's over,
or even when the game starts.
So we're gonna have to fix that.
Now we can do something similar
to how we handled our game over
text and our restart button,
but honestly I'm pretty lazy
and I don't want to just turn all
of these buttons and
texts off individually.
And then I have to turn
them on again and it's the-
it's a whole it's a whole thing.
So, we can actually cheat a little bit,
and we can use a really nice little tip.
So, if we right click on
canvas, we're going to create
a new empty object.
And I'm going to rename our
game object 'title screen',
because this will be
where store all of the
different objects related
to the title screen.
And in fact,
if I select all of the different text
and buttons for the title.
So I can select my title
text shift click down
to the hard button.
Left click and drag into the title screen,
now they're all nested
underneath the title screen.
In fact, I can do something
super useful and easy.
If I disable the title screen game object,
all of the objects underneath
it actually disable too.
So, with this handy little
trick, I can turn off
and on our title screen
whenever I need too.
In our game manager script,
I'm going to need a reference
to that object, so make it public.
We'll call it a 'game object'
since it's just a game object.
And then it'll be the
title screen game object.
Now I'm going to make
sure in my game manager,
that I assigned the
title screen so I'm going
to left click and drag
the title screen object
into the little slot.
And then I'll save that.
And then I'm going to add in
one last little bit of code,
in our start game.
So, when our game has
started, I'm actually going
to get the title screen game object,
and we're going to disable it,
so we'll set active to false.
So now, this should turn
off our title screen.
If we do a quick test, we should now,
when I click one of these buttons,
have our title screen disappear.
There you go, awesome!
So now we can get back
to playing our game,
and then when we lose the game,
we can restart,
and play all over again.
So what you're gonna do is
in your canvas make sure
to right click and create an empty object.
You're going to rename that
empty object the title screen
because that's what will be holding all
of our title screen elements.
We're going to take out title
text, our easy, our medium,
and our hard button and drag
them into our title screen,
so that they're nested as child objects.
In our game manager script,
you're going to make sure
to create a variable for that
title screen game object.
Make sure you assign it in unity as well.
And then in your start game,
you're going to set the
title screen game object
to inactive. You're going to disable it
when we use the start game
method when we click a button.
So now it's your turn.
(game music)