- [Instructor] Our title
screen is now looking amazing,
but we do have this problem
where we're not actually
starting the game.
The game has already started.
And we can actually
click all of these boxes,
but, in fact, we can
also click these buttons,
which is helpful.
And down in the bottom you can see
we know which button was clicked.
In fact, if I squeeze between this button
I can restart the game, so that's fun.
So I actually need to fix that
and actually start our game.
Now, in our game manager's script,
since this is the script
that's managing all the different states
that our game is going through.
Like restarting and game over,
we'll add a start game method into this,
so we don't have to keep immediately
starting the game on start.
So, we'll add a new method,
we'll make it public,
so we can use it outside of this class.
It'll be void, and it'll
be called start game.
Luckily, we've already written
code to start our game.
So, we're just gonna use that.
In our start method here,
you can see that we have
our different settings.
So we'll take all of these
and we'll cut them out
of our start method,
and we'll paste all of that
code into our start game.
So now when the game is started,
we know that the game is set to active.
Our score is reset,
and then we can start
spawning all of our enemies.
Make sure we save,
and then, in our difficulty button script,
we're actually going to need a reference
to the game manager,
just like we did in our target script.
So this will be private,
and we just need to get our game manager,
and we'll call it the game manager,
because that's what it is.
Now, in our start method,
we also need to get a
reference to that game manager.
So we'll get our game manager variable,
and we'll set it or assign it
to the game manager game object.
So, if we use game
object in our hierarchy,
we will find the object
that's called game manager.
And then once we've found that object,
we'll need to get its component,
which is handily also
called the game manager.
And then in our set difficulty method,
we can now use our game manager.
And we can use the start game
method, that we wrote before.
So, if we test our game now,
nothing should happen when we press play.
None of those crates are spawning,
but then, if we press one of our buttons,
let's go for easy mode,
there you go you've got
some crate spawning.
And then our game should go over,
get the game over, cool.
So we're almost there,
but at least now we can start the game
when we press one of the buttons.
So, what you're gonna do
in your game manager script,
you're going to create a new
method called start game.
And then we can just grab all of the code
from our start method at the top,
and paste it down into start game.
In our difficulty button script,
create a variable for the game manager.
Make sure to find that
game manager in the scene,
and then get the component
of its game manager script,
so we can get the variables.
And then, in set difficulty,
you can then call game
manager, dot start game,
so, when we click one of the buttons,
it'll then run this line
of code and start our game.
Now it's your turn.